It's over, for now.

Day 01118: Thursday, 2018 March 29

Drudgery

I was in a hurry when I wrote up my entry last night due to the website update that needed to happen before midnight, so I left out a couple things I really shouldn't've. I'm not sure if it's the temporarily-dropped censorship (Look! You can actually read this entry!), the fact that I'm now out of that terrible course, or the fact that I let out all my building frustration into the conclusion for the paper due yesterday, but I feel much better today. I really poured my heart into that conclusion. I tried to point out several idiotic problems I had to deal with while also taking responsibility for the failure of the research. I think I failed in that regard. The conclusion came out very snarky. The claim I made that I need to be less ambitious in choosing a topic? What a joke. I didn't give up on my ambitions in writing up my paper. I simply redirected them. The fact it that the research could have succeeded at a better school; one without the arbitrary limitations. My target audience ceased to be the general public; it became the university faculty. And my message was no longer one of how we need to fix our purchasing behaviour; it became one of how the school's idiotic restrictions are a hindrance to education. Will anyone do something about this? No. Probably not. But I've expressed my view to the one person within the school that will read that paper, and maybe they'll see some of the problems Even though they'll do nothing about them, maybe they'll start to notice little cracks in the facade the school puts on; maybe they'll start to see things I didn't even mention. Ha! How's *that* for ambition? I'm trying to make the professor care. They won't, but that doesn't mean I didn't try my best.

As planned, I biked to Eugene today to take the exams. I anticipated that they'd be difficult; a time limit on the maths problems and no access to my textbook and calculator, for starters. The maths final turned out to be ten questions long though. It was really nothing. The English final was forty questions long, but as expected, the questions were a combination of the school patting itself on the back for how "great" it is, useless garbage that I knew before the term started, and useless garbage that I still don't know offhand, but could easily deduce because it was a multiple-choice test and most of the options were clearly wrong. I need to stop getting myself worked up for these proctored exams. I did this last time too, but in my defence, I didn't have any way to know what to expect last time. This time, I should have known better. I bet these proctored exams are just something the school does to keep their accreditation or something. The proctored exams aren't the more difficult exams, they're just the exams for courses that are chosen based on some other criteria. It could be random. Or it could be courses some regulator has them proctor. I don't know, and to be honest, I'm only mildly curious at best.

Catching up

The term is over, so it's time to catch up on what I've not had the energy to do. I tried to pay my mother a visit, but she wasn't around. I also finally got the key duplicated and the spare hidden where I can access it if needed. Next, I dropped by the bike shop to claim the warrantee on that jammed lock. I misplaced the warrantee instructions though, so I wasn't sure I've be able to make the exchange until I found them. Thankfully, the bike shop representative was familiar with the process and just swapped locks for me. I didn't think about it before I left, but they took my receipt. If this happens again, I won't have proof of my purchase. Hopefully I won't need it if that day comes.

I should have worked on fining my tax returns today, but I didn't. I needed some time to recuperate from the difficult term that just ended.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

No driving instructor after all

Day 01119: Friday, 2018 March 30

Minetest log

I've now gotten enough of the minequest_doors code written to make the wooden door the first item with a usable bonus ability. The interface is still too clunky, but with time, I can fix that.

I've come up with a new idea though, one that emulates a feature from the original minequest plan and emulates a similar feature of one of the later drafts. First, stat affinity can be automatically detected instead of hard-coded. Second, when activating a new bonus with an item that has multiple affinities, a dialogue can be presented to the user letting them choose which to use. Third, each affinity can be used only for one bonus ability at a time. This won't affect the minequest_doors code, aside from the fact I'll be able to remove the stat affinity specification. However, it'll be a rewrite of a large chunk of the minequest code. Even if I were still starting from scratch, it'd be a big undertaking and I'm not sure I'm up for it. Then again, I'd love to have this working from the beginning; from the proof-of-concept stage, and I'd love not to have unintuitive affinities with the wooden items. With the current setup, each wooden item has to choose a single sapling stat to be bound to, even though most wooden items can be crafted from any sort of wood. Players have no way to guess which sapling powers which wooden items until they mess up their bonus decks by overdrawing the power of a particular star. For example, they may accidentally lose half their warp points in such a blunder that they had no way to know would happen without reading the code of every item. It's just not a good system. *sigh* I guess I need to go back to the code and make this new system a reality. If Minetest can handle it, that is. Actually, never mind. I just realised that what I was trying to do is possible in JavaScript, but the dialogue boxes sent in Minetest don't wait for a response; the code just continues. Maybe I'll need to implement a double-slot system, where players have to use two items to get a bonus: one of the preferred drop and one of the item. No drop means no stat affinity is used, which either means statless bonuses can't be used or bonuses that'd normally have an attached stat can be used without a stat. Or I could write some rejection code for such cases ... or eliminate statless bonuses altogether ... I don't know. I guess I have more planning to do here. The current system is flawed though, it needs to be fixed with *something*.

Oh, wait. I keep forgetting that automatic affinity detection isn't a possibility any more. At all. The problem is the saplings. They can't be crafted into anything, but the trees they grow into can. Wooden items should still be usable with the sapling stats, as they're they only things that sapling stats *can* be used for, aside from the saplings themselves. Having a third of the stats only usable with one item each when they logically relate to so many more items is stupid.

By the end of the day, I came up with most of a plan, but it'll require gutting the code I have so far and, to account for saplings, some hacky stuff. I came up with the plan at work though, and I got home late, so I won't go into details until later. Maybe not tomorrow or the next day, as I have stuff going then.

Driving

I told my driving instructor that with April coming up, to let me know when they're available to help me. As I thought, they'd forgotten. They say they'll get back to me last week, but they didn't last time they said that. I don't think they're going to help me after all. They certainly mean to, but they're too busy. It's not going to work out. I might as well accept that now. I won't give up on them until April's over, but I'm certainly giving up all actual hope right now. By the end of April, they start school again. That's when I'll know for sure I was right. I might start the job hunt soon if I find the time, but just tell potential employers I can't start until May.

Cowardice

My head manager has once again showed their cowardice in refusing to deal with customers that ask for a manager. I'm so done with this. I can't wait until I can escape to a better job.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

minequest improves

Day 01120: Saturday, 2018 March 31

Minetest log

I apologise for being vague yesterday about the plan. A coworker was supposed to contact me last night about a thing (personal, don't worry about it) that they wanted me to help with today, but they never did. I needed to rush my journal entry to get some sleep, but it looks like that wasn't necessary. They didn't even call it off, they just left me hanging.

Anyway, the plan for minequest was to set up a two-step process for choosing your bonus abilities. In the first step, you put a countable item into a slot; the copuntable item is then referred to as an "element". Next, you put something that has been crafted from that element (or another of the element itself) into a freshly-opened deck slot to get the bonus ability. A mechanism for allowing items to specify that they're an alternate form of another item was to be implemented, and this was to be used in addition to crafting recipes to figure out the elemental composition of all defined items. Items with an elemental composition but no defined bonus ability were to now be allowed in the deck slots, but instead of showing that item's non-existent ability icon, a question mark icon was to be displayed. All of this has now been implemented. The main thing that *hasn't* been implemented is the movement of items between the deck and elemental slots. Items can be moved in from the player's main inventory or back out to the inventory, but they can't be directly transferred between slots used by this mod. The problem is that the movement rules are complex and I keep having to gut the code. I'm going to be *so* frustrated if I encode the rules in a form the game can understand and I end up having to gut the code again and scrap the rule-encoding. So I'm just disallowing all movement between slots for now. All legal moves can still be achieved using only one extra step, and when I've had time to stabilise the code better, I'll write up the rules properly.

Okay. So. As I kind of touched upon that as a possibility yesterday, this plan of action just removed my option to have bonus abilities that aren't tied to a particular stat. This removes some of the items I need to define abilities for, but also removes some ability ideas I'd come up with, as they're more binary in nature. You either have them or you don't; there's no concept of "levelling" them. For example, I wanted an item to provide access to a sort of shared inventory between all players that used that item in their decks. That is no longer a possibility. Some easy bonuses aren't available now either, such as the portable furnace when using a furnace in your deck.

Of particular frustration to me are a couple of my own mods that define items. renew defines the grinder and compost. What kind of bonus do I provide for *compost*? The grinder's ability should obviously be a portable form of what it does when placed into the world. How do I provide level-up benefits for *that*!? Most frustrating is my blockprotectnodes mod. The nodes deal with anti-vandalism, so obviously the bonus should in some way. However, anti-vandalism is a serious matter and should not in any way have any of its features be dependant on level-up mechanisms; all players should have equal opportunity to have their stuff protected once they craft the nodes. These two ideals are at *direct odds* with each other. How can I possibly satisfy both?!? So anyway, supporting my mod within my own mods is going to be a challenge, as I don't tend to take node definition lightly; I don't define nodes without good reason, so the node I *do* define tend to either important or have strange qualities. I'm not yet at the stage where I need to deal with supporting these nodes yet, as I don't even have my proof-of-concept built, but by the time this thing releases as stable, I'll need to have solved this problem.

I've also revisited my decisions in how to renew materials using renew, with an emphasis this time on what items it allows me to add support for in minequest-related mods. Before, I was trying to turn clay into something countable for minequest. I don't recall the exact reason why it was going to help. This time though, I'm just looking at what items can even be placed into the ability deck at all after I've added renewability. Clay, for example, can be used with iron or any sapling, so I'm leaving it as I had it before. I didn't do an in-depth search, but in particular, I noticed that sand (all varieties), desert stone, and water lilies were given renewability, but not an element. I don't see a way to associate water lilies with an element. It's just not going to happen. Desert stone would be a challenge. I'm not sure I could find a clean way, but in the future, maybe I will. As for sand ... I've tried numerous times to come up with something, and I've had all sorts of crazy ideas, but I didn't have anything solid until today. Now I don't need to have the grinder in renew. It was there because it needed to be, but it doesn't really fit in.

I had a lot of time to think today while away from my computer, unable to work on actually implementing anything. I came up with three distinct plans for changing sand into a countable item, each more refined than the last. In my final draft for the day, lava is no longer able to harden into desert stone; it always cools into stone or a mineral. Cobble already drops gravel in renew, but in this new version, it'll additionally drop silver sand whenever it does. I guess the sand accounts for the missing stone to allow for air between the rocks in the gravel. Four silver sand can be crafted with one iron lump to give all four that reddish desert sand colour. If eight sand are crafted with the iron lump, eight mid-tone sand are gotten instead. Silver sand and desert sand can likewise be crafted together to get the mid-tone sand. Finally, desert sandstone can be smelted into desert stone, and for consistency, silver sandstone can be cooked into grey stone. The main benefit of all this, of course, is the removal of that grinder. It doesn't belong in that simple renewal mod. However, this also pulls everything made of sand and stone of any type into the list of items I can support in minequest. I do have two complaints still though. This necessarily ties the silver sand stat to the gravel stat. The twinned stats are redundant, strictly speaking. Also, again because of the twinning, this makes the automated background chooser will chose the same node to use as a background for both drops. The issue of the redundant stat is something I can live with. As for the duplicated background, all I have to do is override the autochooser's choice, which I'm already doing for cotton, wheat, cotton seed, and wheat seed.

I think the only thing left that I've given renewability to without making tied to at least one element is the water lilies I mentioned. As said before, I'm firmly of the opinion that those can't be tied to an element in a non-hacky way, so I'm done. This could be the final version of renew until a new stable version of Minetest Game brings more items to add renewability to.

I still need to write up the code for all this though. It's late and I've got to get up in the morning. This'll have to wait for another day.

Work

The boss was needlessly being a jerk again today. I really do need to get out of there. The funny thing is that nearly everyone that's been there thinks the head manager is a jerk, but most of the time, I'm oblivious to it myself. He just usually can't get under my skin so easily. A number of factors are likely making me more receptive to it than usual though; some good, some bad. And as far as I can predict, none of the likely factors are going away any time soon. I need somewhere I can be happier. I guess ... I'd rather have the Minequest Modpack done than have a new job. I've wanted minequest for ages, and the fact that it's been broken into several mods doesn't change that. I'll probably get to job-hunting if there's time after I have the stuff I know to do in the code done. I'll hit creative block at some point, and that's when I'll job hunt if school isn't taking too much of my energy.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.